

Summary

Graphic designer and web developer with 5 years of experience working with clients to create products and assets that are impactful and effective. Works closely with clients to build relationships and cultivate creative solutions, engagements, and experiences. Has a deep interest and experience in emerging technologies (especially in augmented and virtual reality).

Education

Full Stack Web and Mobile Development, Nucamp Coding Bootcamp
 BFA Printmaking, Maryland Institute College of Art, Baltimore MD

Professional Experience

2019 – 21 Graphic Designer/Production Artist, Denial Print Company, Folsom PA

- •Led the design team in projects for clients including both digital and printed collateral.
- •Created engagement on the business' social media platforms through posts and stories.
- •Revised the company's website by building a new template and standardized graphics.
- •Conducted an internal audit to improve quality control, workflow, and production output.
- •Created automations in the pre-press stage of projects, rapidly increasing productivity and accuracy.
- •Generated online sales forms hosted on the company's web page, increasing sales replies exponentially.
- •Managed the digital printing department in project queues, quality control, and digital product finishing. Tasks: Design, Ideation, Prepress, Finishing, Quality Control, File Management, Product Finishing, Large Format Printing.

2018 Intern, Applied Image LLC, Freehold NJ

- •Produced artwork for murals under the supervision of the graphic design team.
- Produced large format and environmental graphics for clients.
- •Up-kept studio quality and performed general maintenance on printers and plotters Tasks: Pre-press, Finishing, Printing, Plotting, Weeding, Laminating, Studio Maintenance.

2016 – 18 Studio Supervisor, MICA, Baltimore MD

- •Managed the digital printing studio at the Printmaking Department facilities.
- •Established the foundation of the department's risograph press by producing color charts and running workshops for students.
- •Educated students on fine art digital printing, screen printing, and best studio practices.
- •Acted as a consultant in digital printing processes for visiting artists and the student body.

 Tasks: Pre-press, Consultant, Educator, Hosted regularly scheduled workshops and office hours.

2014 – 18 Studio Assistant, Quentin Mosely, Jimmy Joe Roche, Baltimore MD

- •Designed and created custom 16mm film hardware for the short film Skin of Man.
- •Printed cover art, inserts, and advertisement materials for the music label Ultra Violet Light.
- •Assisted in constructing a large public installation for the first annual Light City Baltimore.



Daniel Langston

dan.t.langston@gmail.com / 609-556-0229 / dantlangston.com

Projects

2022 PetSense - UI Designer, Developer

PetSense is an application and wearable device for your pet that brings their health data and well being straight to your fingertips and desktop. This is an ongoing solo project in the prototyping and research phases.

2021 Vocabulize - UI Designer / Front-End Developer

Vocabulize is a visual learning aid created as part of MintBean's hackathon. Created brand guidelines, prototype, and user interface for the application. Developed the front-end of the site with custom graphics, and variable styles to ensure consistency.

2018 The Skin of Man - Production / Development

The Skin of Man (2020) is a psychological horror film. This project was shot on 16mm film using a hand coating process. Assisted in research and testing these processes for practical use at the artist's home studio. Constructed custom hardware for exposing the film in a consistent method at home.

2017-18 Ultra Violet Light - Design Consultant / Printer

Ultra Violet Light is the premiere music label for spacial sound, analog synthesis, and soundscape exploration. Reviewed and made adjustments to packaging and marketing materials. Created the work through unconventional methods including laser cutting and engraving, screen printing, and risograph printing.

2016 Light City Baltimore - Design Assistant / Construction

Light City Baltimore is a festival and art showcase that began in 2016. Worked directly with an artist in developing and constructing their light installation. Constructed scaffolding and fixated 50 neon tubes over the harbor's water. Assisted in wiring analog electronics.

Software

Adobe Suite: Illustrator, Photoshop, Fresco, After Effects, Premiere, Indesign, Audition, Medium, Spark, Spark AR, Rhinoceros, Google Analytics

Languages

HTML, CSS/SCSS/Sass, Javascript, React, Redux

Skills

Proven ability to work both independently and in teams.

Natural team leader.

Excellent communication skills through active listening.

Offers dynamic creative solutions to user engagement and perspective.

Recognized ability to give meaningful and constructive feedback to teams and projects.

Demonstrated adaptability when tackling new technologies and trends.

Invested in learning and expanding skill sets.